Guide to the Democratic Socialists of America Records TAM.105
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Records: State chapter files, Oregon--Wyoming, early-mid 1980s; several files of minutes of the National Organizing/Executive Com mittee[s]; a file from a Young Socialist Executive Committee meeting, 1990; Local Development Fund Files; a think file of administrative materials from 1981, including some Harrington circular letters; several DSA Commission files, including Anti-Racism, from 1994, 1981-1994 (Box 18A)
- Records: Incomplete National administrative records, including Executive Committee minutes, 1980s-early 1990s; several files on the periodical Socialist Forum; and several Local Development project files., 1980-1992 (Box 19)
- Records: DSOC national administrative files, ca. 1976-81, including several files of meeting minutes, a Newsletter of the Democratic Left Search Committee file, Personnel and Management Commitee, circulars and reports, surveys of locals; in addition there are several files for California chapters, for cities beginning with the letter "S", from the latter 1980s., 1976-1987 (Box 20)
- Records: Minutes of the variously titled National Executive Committee, 1978-1992; one thick files "DSOC/DL" containing a computer printout of what may be a combined membership/subscriber list from 1980; and one file containing an address to the National Board of DSA by Michael Harrington, February, 1983. (Box 20A)
- Records: Chapter files from New York--Texas, mid-late 1980s, including newsletters; several thick files of miscellaneous materials, most printed ephemera or periodicals of other organizations., ca. 1979-ca. 1988 (Box 21)
- Records: Regional and local bulletins, 1973-75 (2 files); Chapter files, 1980s, for states from California--Pennsylvania, including publications; severl thick files of miscellaneous materials, some administrative, most printed ephemera and publications of other organizations, 1973-ca. 1988 (Box 21A)
- Records: Two bound volumes of handwritten National Office Committee minutes, 1973-74; National Executive Committee minutes, 1985-88; one thick file on the New York Labor Forum, 1976; one folder with a letter to MH from John Kenneth Galbraith, Jul 1, 1975; and several topical files, 1973-1988 (Box 22)
- Records: About half the box consists of National Executive Committee minutes, 1985-88; two thick files from 1978-79 containing correspondence, much pertaining to the Newsletter of the Democratic Left; a thick envelope containing hundreds of membership cards (undated); and miscellaneous printed ephemera., 1978-1988 (Box 23)
- Records: Minutes, 1984-90 from the variously titled National Executive Committee and the National Board - included are various reports; there are also several files of materials received from the Democratic Party., 1984-1990 (Box 23A)
- Records: National Board, 1987-92, 1987-1992 (Box 24)
- Records: Chicago Red Squad Files on the New American Movement, 1971-74, 1971-1974 (Box 24A)
- Records: The bulk of the material is from the 1987 convention, with a few files from the 1985 convention; a thick file of administrative material titled "Jimmy Higgins"; miscellaneous printed ephemera, ca. 1981-1987 (Box 25)
- Records: Mostly 1991 convention; also several files on 1983 and 1984 "Conferences"; two files on the Youth Section (1980, 83); several topical files, 1980-1991 (Box 26)
- Records: Youth Secton files, 1981-85; also several files of publications and printed ephemera, 1981-1985 (Box 27)
- Records: Socialist International, 1976-80; Bylaws, 1989; Labor Commission, 1991, 1976-1991 (Box 27A1)
- Records: Socialist International, 1972, 1979, 1983 (Box 27A2)
- Records: Youth Section Winter Conferences, 1987-90; YS Keylist Mailings, 1980-81; Othe YS materials; Several National Board/Executive Committe meetings, latter 1980s; several folders of loose miscellaneous administrative records and ephemera, including a small amount of Harrington correspondence, 1980-1990 (Box 28)
- Records: Youth Section, 1980-88: chapter, charters, minutes, reports, publications, including Days of Decision, job search for national director; One file "Past Speaking Dates [Harrington]", including MH correspondence., 1980-1988 (Box 29)
- Records: Various administrative records and topical files, 1980-88, including 1980 leadership retreat; Youth Section records, 1980s, including search for national director, and several issues of Days of Decision; file on Billy Bragg tour, 1988, file on University in Society Project, 1986; note: last box in CS aisle 27, 1980-1988 (Box 29A)
- Records: Records: About half the box is devoted to student activism (peace, against cuts in funding for educational and social programs, e.g. Student Alliance for an Immediate Freeze); one file on Harrington speaking engagements, invitations, etc., but little or no letters by MN; one thick file on anti-apartheid activity; various administrative records, including detailed handwritten notes for an undated national conference note: first box in CS aisle 13; note: 57th box, 1982-1990 (Box 30)
- Records: various DSOC records, 1979-84, including staff meetings notes, staff search file, mailing lists; issues of the Discussion Bulletin and Socialist Forum; the remainin quarter of the box contains NAM Discussion Bulletins, and a file of various administrative materials., 1979-1984 (Box 30A)
- Records: DSOC Youth Section, principally conference materials, 1979-83., 1979-1983 (Box 31)
- Records: about half the box concerns the 1989 Convention; Youth Section records, 1979-83, including correspondence, Office Committe, and conferences comprise the rest of the box, along with several issues of Socialist Forum., 1979-1989 (Box 32)
- Records: New American Movement, 1970s-early 1980s, including conventions, locals, publications and reports, and one file of DSA 1989 Convention minutes., 1970s-1989 (Box 32A)
- Records: Youth Section Executive Committee minutes, 1989; Key Lists; one thick file on North Shore (NY) chapter of Mobilization for Survival, 1988-1992 (Box 33)
- Records: Correspondence, 1979; Topical and activities files, 1980s; some Youth Section records, 1979-1990 (Box 33A)
- Records: Socialist International and DSOC, including correspondence, with the SI and its constitutent members, some of which is Michael Harrington's, and various reports, position papers, etc., 1974-1982 (Box 34)
- Records: about half the box consists of 1983 Convention (Detroit) materials; New Directions caucus; some materials on joint DSOC/NAM letterhead; various administrative records as recent as 1992; several files of materials accumulated or created by Saul Wellman, former Communist active in Washington DC / Maryland chapters., 1983-1992 (Box 34A)
- Records: New American Movement, 1970s: chapters, mailings, conferences, reports from organizers, 1970-1979 (Box 35)
- Records: Conventions, 1980, 1983, 1985; NAM convention, 1978; one file, DOSC/Left Unity, 1978-80, 1977-1985 (Box 35A)
- Records: New American Movement, 1977-82: topical and activity files, with some administrative files; contains circulars, correspondence, reports, publications, etc., 1977-1982 (Box 36)
- Records: DSOC/DSA, NAM: DSA 1983 convention; DSOC minutes--nat'l Board, National Interim Committee, 1981-82; includes discussion of merger with NAM; also various topical files and adminsitive materials, including reports; NAM: discussion of, and conflict over merger with DSOC, Bulk, 1979-1982; 19762-1986, bulk 1979-1982 (Box 37)
- Records: Key Lists, 1982-87; Michael Harrington engagements, 1985-87, i.e., speaking tours, mostly administrative correspondence and related materials, with little or no MH correspondence, 1982-1987 (Box 38)
- Records: Michael Harrington speaking engagements, travell including datebooks, letters to MH, logistics and finances, 1983-89; the remaining third of the box contains National Interim Committee minutes and related documents, 1982-87., 1982-1989 (Box 39)
- Records: States and Chapters, Kentucky--New York; Youth Section files, including Executive Committee, National Office Committee, 1985-87, correspondence, and a 1982 conference; a thick file on anti-draft activity, mainly Committee Against Registration and the Draft; DSA 1983 convention ballots, 1980-1983 (Box 40)
- Records: about half the box is devoted to the 1980 NYC Mobilization Against the Draft demonstration; some Executive Committee minutes, 1986-87; Staff Meetings, 1982; Key Lists; one thick file "Transitional Economic Program," Socialist International file with letters to Harrington, 1985-86, and from the same date span, a file of letters to Harrington marked "pending, hold", 1980-1987 (Box 41)
- Records: DSOC early years, 1972-75, resolutions, minutes, correspondence a folder of National Interim Committee biographies, circular letters: DSA 1986-87, circular letters (a few from Harrington), correspondence, minutes, reports, etc.; a few files on the New American Movement, mostly on its founding, 1972; a 1974 organizational perspective document by Bodgan Denitch., 1972-1987 (Box 42)
- Records: Audiotapes (36): including League for Industrial Democracy/Young Peoples Socialist League Christmas Conference, 1970 (approx 18 tapes); Labor Institute Conference, April 1968 (approx 11 tapes); N. Hill, Michael Harrington, six tapes, undated., 1968, 1970, undated (Box 43)
- Records: about half the box is devoted to the 1980 Mobilization Against the Draft demonstration; much of the remainder consists of several files of what appear to be Mobilization for Survival records, including its Religious Task Force and Gay Task Force; also materials from a 1980 conference., 1979-1980 (Box 44)
- Records: Naational Executive Committee files, 1982-88; staff meeting notes; files on peace movement activity, including Pro-Lifers for Survival; Institute for Democratic Socialism (two thick files, ca. 1980-82), 1980-1988 (Box 45)
- Records: the bulk of the box is concerned with a DSA sponsored 1980 conference on Eurosocialism, and includes some Harrington correspondence, including a letter to Francois Mitterand (in French) in the "Keynoters" file; there are also several DSA Feminist Commission files; there are also several files on an early 1980s membership recruitment campaign, 1980-1988 (Box 46)
- Records: Eurosocialism conference, including three-ring binder with conference materials, also, thank you letters, some from Harrington; 1978 event celebrating Harrington's 50th birthday; Debs-Thomas dinner, 1975; miscellaneous DSOC administrative materials, 1975-1980 (Box 47)
- Records: bulk of box contains membership files, including questionnaires and a NYC membership map; a file on 1987 convention delegates; Esecutive Committee minutes, 1990-93; Newsletter files; topical and event files., 1984-1993 (Box 48)
- Records: Young Socialist Alliance; University activism; anti-racism activism; msicellaneous topical and administrative files, 1977-ca. 1987 (Box 49)
- Records: Justice For All files, 1987 (anti-poverty, economic justice); 1981 dinner honoring Willy Brandt; peace and disarmament files; several Mobilization for Survival records files, ca. 1980-ca. 1987 (Box 50)
- Records: several Justice for All files; various administrative records, including some correspondence re Harrington speaking engagements; thick file of resumes for an unidentified position; topical files, most concerned with poverty, inequality, etc., 1980s (Box 51)
- Records: about half of the box contains 1983 DSA internal documents from various policy discussions, retreats, etc.; one thick file of correspondence, 1983-84; correspondence with local DSOC organizations, 1976-79, 1976-1985 (Box 52)
- Records: bulk of box is Justice for All files, including circular letters from Harrington, 1987; also National Executive Committee minutes, 1984; correspondence with local DSOC groups, 1979-80; Feminits Commission directory, undated; various topical and administrative files., 1979-1987 (Box 53)
- Records: bulk concerns 1985 convention, including membership and delegate information; one file of correspondence of Bill Spence (Youth Section), 1986; Feminist Commission file, 1984-1988 (Box 54)
- Records: 1980s files on black liberation, Native Americans, prisons and political prisoners; Hunter college NYC student activism file, 1989; files on other organizations, including the John Brown Anti-Klan Committee, ca. 1980-ca. 1989 (Box 55)
- Records: Executive Director Maxine Phillips correspondence, 1983-84; Democratic Agenda conference, 1979, Washington, DC; Democratic Left correspondence, and other DA materials; 1986 DSA office opening gala; miscellaneous topical files and administrative materials, 1979-1986 (Box 56)
- Records: National Executive Committe, 1982-86; Religious Caucus, New Directions Caucus; Tribute to Moe Foner, 1981; files related to 1988 Democratic Party events; several state and local chapter files., 1980-1989 (Box 57)
- Records: Contains files, mostly 1980s, on international solidarity, pro-democracy struggles, e.g., Central America, East Timor, Northern Ireland, anti-Gulf War, and draft resistance, 1980., 1978-1991 (Box 58)
- Records: National Mobilization Against the Draft (March 22, 1980 demonstration); several anti-nuclear weapons files, 1978-79, 1978-1980 (Box 59)
- Records: American Solidarity Movement (with labor, also voter registration, early 1980s); Feminist Commission, Structure Committee Report, 1982-83; Justice for All Campaign (anti-poverty, early 1980s); Poverty Conference Proposal, by Harrington, 1984; Poverty correspondence, Harrington, 1987; DSA renewal campaigns, 1982-83, 1980-1987 (Box 60)
- Records: NYC DSA, including executive committee minutes, cadre lists, early 1980s; National Office Communications, 1979-80; Economic policy reports and comments thereon; Reproductive rights, 1979-1985 (Box 61)
- Records: "Political Cases", some re government surveillance and rights of givernment employees; notable names include Ron Dellums, Jane Fonda, Black Panther Party, Peter Boehmer vs. Nixon; 1970s, 1974-1975 (Box 62)
- Records: DSOC-DSA, DSA Youth section, 1982-88; a miscellany of administrative records and topical files; includes a folder of Central America correspondence with a few Harrington items; a number of the files are from the NYC DSA chapter, 1982-1988 (Box 63)
- Records: Student Peace Mobilization Project folder, 1980-82, with some Harrington letters; International Union of Socialist Youth, early 1980s reports, etc.; Institute for Democratic Socialism Youth Conference, 1979; Youth Organizing Fund, 1979; DSA Summer Conference, 1983, 1979-1984 (Box 64)
- Records: Youth Conference, 1982; Democratic Left Advisory Committee, 1984; various DSA committees: Restructuring, Finance; National Executive Committee, mid-1980s; Speaking Tours/Bureau 1990; clippngs on DSA and for Harrington, 1980s, 1982-1990 (Box 65)
- Records: Rainbow Coalition, 1987-88; DSA Health Project, 1991-92; Women's March, 1992; Democratic Left; natioanl Offce: circulars, reports; Electoral Action Task Force; Speaking tours; Correspondence with New Democratic Party (Canada), 1987-1993 (Box 66)
- Records: DSOC meetings and conventions, 1973-76; Democratic Party work, including campaign to Make harrington a delegate to convention; "[Pete] Hammill/Harrington" folder (clippings); Socialist Scholars Conference, 1992; Sherri Levine Correspondence, 1987, Education Director' folder "Harrington, Government Spying On., 1973-1992 (Box 67)
- Records: DSOC letter 1970s-early 1980s topical files: peace, anti-nuclear, energy conservation, others; National Student Peace Day, 1984, ca. 1976-1984 (Box 68)
- Records: Youth Section, including correspondence, Jeremy Karpatkin, Nat'l Organizer; Chapter Repors; National Student Peace Day; New Jersey and NYC YS chapters; Central America, 1980-1985 (Box 69)
- Records: One file of Harrington correspondence, 1987; Miwcellaneous topical and administrative files, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 70)
- Records: Democratic Party Convention (1988) DSA activity; one file, DP 1984 convention, 1984, 1988 (Box 71)
- Records: Youth Section, 1987, several files; bulk of box consists of reference material-- "white papers", reports, and some like DSA materials, 1981-1987 (Box 72)
- Records: About half of the box is Youth Section materials from the latter 1980s, including the Hiring Ctte for a nat'l Director, 1987; YS conference, 1993; DSA: North Carolina meeting, 1988, some national office records, including correspondence of director Michael Lighty., 1987-1993 (Box 73)
- Records: DSA Conventions, 1995, 1997; "DSA Mission" folder; Chapter files (MD, Northern VA, Pittsburgh, Sacramento, etc.); Nationasl Executive Committee resolution, 1981-88; National Board Resolutions, 1981-1998 (Box 74)
- Records: 1995 convention; Structure Committee; National Political Committee, including minutes notebook; Organizing Manual; Local Sruvey returns, 1991; Reports and other writings, some annotated, 1991-1995 (Box 75)
- Records: "Manuscript, New Yorker article (Harrington), 1987; National Political Committee, 1991-92, 1997; Assistant to Director Search, 1991; some international correspondence; Organizing Institute, 1993; National Youth organizer Dinah Leventhal's reports, 1990; various administrative and topical files, 1987-1997 (Box 76)
- Records: Harrington writings: End of the Left? [1985], American Socialism, shorter writings; writings about MH, including Richard Flacks on Harrington and Tom Hayden; National Executive Committee Minutes 1985; Religion and Socialism Committee (about 1/3 box; Labor Day 1991; Democratic Left, 1978-1991 (Box 77)
- Records: Youth Section, 1991-92; Campaign for Peace in the Middle East; dsanet, 1995; Democratic Left, 1989-91; DSA Winter Retreat, 1996, 1989-1996 (Box 78)
- Records: Almost entirely Youth Section; American Student Mobilization; DSA leadership retreat, 1989, a few other DSA anad topical files, including Health Care, 1988-1994 (Box 79)
- Records: Michael Harrington's death and memorial; one file of Harrington correspondence, 1988; Committees and Commissions, latter 1980s; Budget, 1989; "History--DSA/DSOC" [undated]; Robert Delson correspondence with DSA, 1990., 1985-1990 (Box 80)
- Records: Harrington Correspondence: receeived, 1988 (includes ltr from Bill Moyers asking him to appear on public television), sent, 1989, "Harrington Current" - speaking engagements, 1988-89; Clips about Harrington, 1982-89; one thick file of Harrington writings; file on Harrington's receipt of Debs-Thomas award, Bulk, 1988-1989; 1982-1989 (Box 81)
- Records: Articles by and clippings about Harrington; Death of Harrington, clippings and other materials; bibliography of Harrington's writings, 1946-74; Fundraising; some National Office Correspondence, 1990s; DSA constitution, discussions on, 1980s; Education Committee, 1991, 1985-1991 (Box 82)
- Records: seven videocassettes about "Economic Insecurity"; five audiocassette binders [each holds 12 cassettes]: two Institute for Democratic Socialism conferences, focus is economics and politics; the other three binders are on various policy issues and appear to be tied to Democratic Party Conventions or congresses in the 1980s (Box 83)
- Records: Financial and Budget, 1987-93; Director Michael Lighty speaking tour, 1992; Convention, 1993; "California State-Wide Org" file; Commissions: Environment, Anti-Racism; file on "Recruitment Video"; Religious Socialism correspondence (one file), 1987-1993 (Box 84)
- Records: One thick file, Socialist Internatnional correspondence, 1980-81; National Political Committee minutes [binders] 1997-98; Youth Section conferences, 1981-94; clippings on Harrington's death, 1981-1998 (Box 85)
- Records: all Youth Section, 1987-95, including National Office Collective Minutees, 1993-95; Executive Committee minutes, 1986-90; Keylists, late 1980s; "Chapter Surveys, 1992", topical files, including Middle East, Apartheid, 1987-1995 (Box 86)
- Records: all Youth Section, 1983-95. Includes, Keylists, conventions and conferences, correspondence, an organizing manual, a proposal to hire a California organizer, reports and political statements, a file on The Activist/Labor Activist, 1983-1995 (Box 87)
- Records: DSA, including Executive Committee minutes, 1986-88; Harry Britt tour, 1983 (SF City Supervisor); files on speaking events for Manning Marable and Cornell West; Harrington Natioanl tour, 1982; Central America Speakers' Bureau, 1984; NYC DSA, 1979-86, including minutes, Labor Forum, 1991 convention, 1979-1991 (Box 88)
- Records: DSA conventions, 1995, 1997; leadership retreats, early 1990s; correspondence, including emails; Youth Section, 1993-95: conference, 1994, correspondence, several chapter files, 1990-1997 (Box 89)
- Records: DSA national conventions, 1993, 1995; Key Lists, 1993 (Box 90)
- Records: National Political Committee, 1992-98; NPC subcommittees; Convention, 1993; Keylists 1992-93, 1992-1998 (Box 91)
- Records: National Political Committee and its Steering Committee, 1994-95; Issues of Religious Socialism, 1982-85., 1982-1995 (Box 92)
- Records: Feminist Commission, 1980-88; "Mission Retreat" 1997; National Politicall Committee, 1997 [incomplete]; committee and topical files, 1990s; Youth Section, 1996, 1980-1997 (Box 93)
- Records: National Convention, 1995, Labor Committee, 1995; Topical files, 1995; "Old Chapter Info" file, 1993; Religion and Socialism Commission, 1993; Socialist Scholars Conference, 1994-96, 1994-1996 (Box 94)
- Records: National Political Committee and Steering Committee, 1996-97 [incomplete]; Education Committee, 1993-94 [incomplete]; Billy Bragg, 1992; "Organizational Documents--Constitution and Merger Agreement, 1983; Commissions: Feminist, Riligion and Socialism, ohters, 1990s; Nurses Caucus Newsletter, 1993, 1983, 1992-1997 (Box 95)
- Records: Periodicals" Not Far Enough, 1982-88 (Feminist Commission), Labor Voice, 1988 (Labor Commission), Our Struggle/Nuestra Lucha, 1988-89 (Latino, Afro-American and Anti-Racism Commissions), Religious Socialism, 1985-86; Local Literature Survey, 1998; National Political Committee, 1995 [incomplete], 1982-1998 (Box 96)
- Records: about half university chapters, no order, late 1980s; Convention, 1995; National Political Committee 1997 retreat; Think Tank project, 1996; Global Justice Task Force, 1994-95; Budget Committee, 1997, 1987-1997 (Box 97)
- Records: New American Movement, 1974-80; Socialist Standard, 1987, Organize (DSA Activists), 1986-87, Nuestra Lucha, 1984-85; California local chapter files, 1980s, 1974-1987 (Box 98)
- Records: Computer Disks. 3.5 inch (>100), some labeled, ca. 1994-ca. 2000 (Box 99)
- Records: Computer discs, 3.5 inches (>100), 1990s, ca. 1994-ca. 1999 (Box 100)
- Records: Membership surveys, 1995-98; Health Activists Digest (DSA), Summer 1980s; Democratizing Education (NAM), 1981, 1981-1982, 1995-1998 (Box 101)
- Records: Surveys and membership renewals, 1995 (Box 102)
- Records: Membership surveys, 1998; International Committee, one undated file; Youth Secton, minutes, 12/30/83;several issues of The Activist (YS), 1986, 1983-1998 (Box 103)
- Records: Membership surveys, 1995; Youth Section, several files, 1985-86; Days of Decision, 1981-85, 1981-1995 (Box 104)
- Records: Videocassettes-- DSA meetings, 1981-2001; also a few talks by Harrington, Barbara Ehrenreich, 1987-2001 (Box 105)
- Records: Education Commssion, including retreat files, early 1990s; topical files, mostly economy, poverty, labor, containing circulars, reports, etc,; Several issue each of the Plant Closings Bulletin (1981), DSOC, and the Third World Socialist, 1984 (Institute for Democratic Socialism, 1987-1994 (Box 106)
- Records: Labor Commission, 1983-90; Hispanic Anti-Racism Commission, 1987; aobut half the box are chapter files, 1990s-2004, many from Pennsylvania, also NY and NJ, 1983-2004 (Box 107)
- Records: Videocassettes of Harrington Talks, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 108)